["Pomp and Circumstance"]
Hola, mis mermes.
Bienvenido a todos.
Realmente es un privilegio estar en la casa del señor, que podamos en libertad adorarlo.
Yo sé que todos nosotros pasamos por momentos tan difíciles en este mundo.
Esta semana, bueno, realmente este último mes ha sido un mes bastante difícil para mí.
Mi papito ha estado enfermo por varios años ya, pero era bastante funcional, pero hace
una semana le pusieron un tubito de alimentación, un pectup, ya no se mueve, ya no tiene contacto
visual con nosotros, y realmente es muy difícil ver a una persona que uno ama tanto y que
fue tan fuerte, tan débil.
Sin embargo, me gozo en el señor, porque uno de los versículos favoritos de mi papi
era Isaías 40-31, pero los que esperan en Jehová tendrán nuevas fuerzas, levantarán
alas como las águilas, correrán, no se cansarán, caminarán y no se fatigarán, y eso es lo
que me mueve.
Sé que mi papi en el cielo volverá a ser ese general que fue aquí en esta tierra fuerte,
que volaba como las águilas, y que inspiró a muchos a venir a los pies de Jesús.
Cuando estamos en necesidad, cuando no podemos hacer nada por aquellos que amamos, quién
es nuestro refugio, nuestro querido Jesús, su amor nos cubre, no hay prueba que su luz
no ayude a superar.
Por eso, descansemos nuestros problemas a los pies de nuestro Salvador.
Oremos.
Padre santo, gracias te doy, señor, porque tu pueblo aquí reunido viene a invocar tu nombre
a hacer, a recibir tu bendición, a tener la seguridad, señor, de que tu luz no se inunda,
que tu espíritu santo nos acompaña y en medio de la tempestad, padre, tú estás ahí,
guiando a nuestra barca, señor, que este día sábado sea de bendición, que podamos
recordar tus promesas y, sobre todo, ser testimonio vivo de tu amor donde quiera que estemos.
En Cristo Jesús, amén.
Bienvenidos a la casa de Dios.
Hace el rey de Dios confiar.
Llegó la hora de adorar a la Señor.
Llegó la hora de escuchar de su amor.
Que el amiguito nos damos sentar y ver calladitos estar.
Pristana atención en adoración.
Llegó la hora de adorar a la Señor.
Llegó la hora de escuchar de su amor.
Y las historias nos van a enseñar.
Hace el rey de Dios confiar.
Llegó la hora de adorar a la Señor.
Llegó la hora de escuchar de su amor.
Que el amiguito nos damos sentar y ver calladitos estar.
Hola, niños.
A ver, vamos a esperar los que vienen.
Ahí vienen otros más.
Vamos a esperar a que todos estén sentaditos y calladitos.
Ok.
Buenos días.
¿Cómo están?
¿Cómo?
Qué bueno.
Ok.
Bueno, el título de la historia de esta mañana es mentirita o mentirota.
¿Ustedes creen que para Dios hay mentiras pequeñas y mentiras grandes?
No.
Ok.
Bien, Josué.
Vas a ayudarme a mostrarles algo a los niños.
Ok.
Aquí yo tengo unos corazones.
Este corazón, como lo ven, tiene alguna mancha?
Está roto?
Es un corazón limpio.
Ok.
Ahora, ¿este corazón qué tiene?
Hoyos.
Tiene hoyos, ¿verdad?
Ahora, Josué, va a mostrarles el último corazón.
¿Qué tiene ese corazón?
Una parte de hoyos.
Curitas.
Ok.
Cuando nosotros mentimos, Jesús nos da unas curitas para sanarnos.
Bien.
Vamos a escuchar la historia.
En la Biblia se cuenta la historia de una pareja que se llama Ananias y Safira.
¿Quién la ha escuchado?
Ok.
Bueno, vamos a repasarla.
En aquel tiempo, en los cristianos, en esa comunidad precisamente no les faltaba nada.
Ellos tenían todo.
Tenían muchas posesiones.
Y entonces la gente que quería dar una posesión, no sé, a otras personas, se las daban a los
apóstoles y ese dinero, los apóstoles la utilizaban para cumplir la misión de la Iglesia
y ayudar a las personas necesitadas.
Pero, ¿qué creen que pasó?
Un día, Ananias y Safira prometieron con todo su corazón que si vendían una posesión
que iba a pasar, la iban a dar, todo el dinero lo iban a dar para Jesús.
Pero, ¿qué creen que pasó?
Cuando vendieron la posesión, vieron que tenían tanto dinero y dijeron,
¿sabes qué?
No vamos a dar todo el dinero.
Vamos a esconder una parte y esa parte le escondieron en su casa.
¿Quién creen ustedes que los vio?
¿Quién?
Dios.
Ellos dijeron, nadie nos está mirando.
Vamos a esconderla aquí, nadie nos mira.
Pero Dios los estaba mirando.
Así que, entonces, fueron con los apóstoles, Ananias les dijo,
aquí es el dinero de lo que hemos vendido.
Y no era todo el dinero, solo era una parte.
Pero Dios le reveló a Pedro, ¿qué creen?
Exactamente, ¿dónde está la otra parte?
Entonces, le dijo, Ananias y Safira no dieron toda la parte del dinero,
la han escondido.
Entonces, le dijo, Pedro, Ananias, ¿tú has pecado contra el Espíritu Santo?
¿Has mentido cuando Ananias escuchó eso?
¿Qué creen que pasó con Ananias?
Calló muerto por mentir, ¿ok?
Después pasó el tiempo y vino ahora su esposa, Safira.
¿Y Safira qué hizo?
¿Ustedes creen que regresó el dinero que tenía escondido?
No, hizo lo mismo, mintió.
Y entonces, Ananias, perdón, Safira, ¿qué creen que pasó con ella?
No se cayó, pero murió, ¿ok?
También murió.
Entonces, ahora quiero preguntarles ustedes, ¿qué creen que para Dios las mentiras son pequeñas o grandes o son igual?
Son iguales.
Esta mañana quiero decirles que cuando Papio Mami les preguntan algo,
no mientan porque la mentira es de Satanás, la Biblia lo dice, ¿ok?
Pero yo creo que todos los niños de la Central del Valle son unos niños bien portaditos
y que siempre dicen la verdad.
Ok, ahora quiero invitar a alguien para orar.
A ver, vamos a invitar a Hazel.
Ven, Hazel, ayúdanos a orar.
No, Hazel no quiere. ¿Alguien más?
A ver, ven, ven, mi amor, tú vas a orar.
Silencio, niños, vamos a orar, ven corazón, ora.
Ven, los dos.
Querido Jesús, gracias, puedes salvar.
Ayúdanos a hacer unos niños obedientes y buenos.
Jesús, amen.
Amen, ya pueden pasar aquí por un papelito para pintar.
Buenos días, hermanos. Feliz sábado.
Tenemos hora del momento de los diezmos y las ofrendas.
Yo creo que es algo muy especial.
Sabían que esta iglesia es una iglesia muy bendecida.
Está hablando con el pastor riso esta semana
y estábamos viendo que nuestra iglesia es la única iglesia hispana
que apoya, que está sola, una sola iglesia,
apoyando a una escuela desde primer grado de primaria
hasta high school en toda la división norteamericana.
¿Se dan cuenta de esto?
Nosotros somos los únicos en mi iglesia sola
que apoya a una escuela completamente.
Yo creo que es una gran bendición.
No somos cualquier iglesia.
Dios nos ha bendecido bastante.
Aquí tenemos muchas talentos, personas que cantan lindo,
predican, tenemos gente que se dedica a los negocios,
empresas, enfermeros, maestros, diferentes profesionales.
Es increíble como Dios nos ha traído
y gracias a Dios estamos reflejando de que somos fieles.
Quiero leerles en éxodo 31,
algo que repasamos en la escuela sabática
sobre cómo Dios nos da dones
y nos da conocimiento de ciencia.
Y él lo hizo con personas con siervos fieles
para que puedan construir el tabernáculo del santuario.
Dice así.
Éxodo 31, de luna al cuatro.
Hablogeo va a Moisés diciendo,
mira, yo he llamado por nombre a Besalel,
hijo de Uri, hijo de Ur, del atribo de Judá
y lo he llenado del espíritu de Dios.
Primero, el espíritu de Dios.
Después, en sabiduría, en inteligencia,
en ciencia y en todo arte para inventar diseños.
Imagínense, Dios nos puede dar todo esto a nosotros.
Poder para tener conocimiento de ciencia y arte.
Y yo creo firmemente que eso ha hecho con personas aquí,
con miembros de la iglesia,
porque tenemos una iglesia realmente gracias a Dios,
próspera, definitivamente.
Y quiero recordarles algo que dice la hermana Gedejuae
en palabras de vida de gran maestro en página 241.
Dice, hemos de alabar a Dios mediante un servicio tangible,
haciendo todo lo que podamos para aumentar la gloria de su nombre.
Dios nos imparte sus dones para que podamos también dar
y hacer así que el mundo conozca su carácter.
Dios nos ha dado estos dones para qué?
Para que el mundo conozca su carácter a través de nosotros.
Y parte de eso es alabar a Dios con nuestras ofrendas,
porque Él ya nos dio estos dones.
Y las ofrendas y los días nos dicen nada más de volver
de lo que Él nos ha dado.
Hermanos, déjanos por favor, se ponen de pie.
Vamos a hablar.
Amante Padre Celestial, señor Gracia,
te damos porque tú eres un Dios bueno, bondadoso,
misericordioso, señor, alabado sea tu nombre, Padre.
En este momento, señor, que tenemos los días y las ofrendas,
te pedimos que tú nos sigas guiando, señor,
con corazones bondadosos, agradecidos hacia ti,
con todos los dones que nos has dado,
todas las bendiciones que nos das diariamente,
tener vida, tener salud, poder trabajar,
poder tener emprendimiento, señor.
Te pido que sigas bendiciendo a los miembros de esta iglesia,
señor, que podamos hacer todo para hacer tu nombre más grande,
en el nombre Jesús.
Amén.
Muy felizado, querida iglesia.
Este es uno de los momentos más, más gratos, más lindos
que la iglesia tiene cuando hay bautismo.
Y más gratos todavía cuando los que se bautizan
son jovencitos de nuestra iglesia.
Y cuando los que se bautizan son amigos
y entre ellos son hermanos.
Así que miren, miren todo lo grato que tenemos
para festejar y estar feliz.
Me gusta la mano bien alto, quien está feliz en este momento
por el bautismo de Damian y de Diego, ¿sí?
Y yo quiero invitar a los amigos, amigos de ellos,
de Damian y de Diego.
La familia también está la mamá.
Tal vez si alguien puede tomar el teléfono de la mamá de Arely
para poder filmar, entonces ella se preocupa
de esa parte que es filmar y disfruta de este momento.
Y está Dani también, el hermanito menor.
Miren, miren.
Miren, miren, miren.
A ver si nos dejan acá el espacio
para que la cámara córranse para este lado, chico.
Vengan para acá, para acá, para acá.
De este lado, ahí.
Ugo, de este lado, de este lado.
Así abren acá el espacio.
Abran aquí así el...
Tenemos familias, tenemos familias de Damian y de Diego
que están mirando alguno desde otro lugar,
desde México, así que los saludamos también.
Por eso necesitamos que se pueda ver
y que la imagen de la cámara pueda entrar por aquí.
Así que ¿cómo están, amigos?
¿Bien? Le dije a Damiana ayer
que tenía que aprenderse 70 versículos de memoria
para decir ahora y estaba un poco asustado, ¿no?
Qué alegría es poder disfrutar este momento.
Quiero decirles, Diego y Damian,
que este va a ser un momento que ustedes van a recordar para siempre.
Entregarse en las manos del Señor Jesús
y comenzar a caminar y comenzar a andar
tomado de su mano es lo mejor que ustedes pueden hacer,
la mejor decisión que ustedes pueden tomar.
Yo me acuerdo cuantos años tenés diez
y Damian, trece.
Damian tiene trece, Diego tiene diez.
Yo cuando me bautizé tenía doce años
y me acuerdo hasta el día de hoy
que pasaron un montón de años ya que ya...
casi que tantos años y uno se empieza a olvidar,
pero me acuerdo de ese momento como un momento grato
y la mejor decisión que puede tomar
es aceptar al Señor Jesucristo como salvador.
A lo largo del camino van a venir
algunos momentos que van a ser difíciles en la vida.
Tal vez algunos de ustedes ya lo están pasando a ese momento,
pero qué grato es saber que no están solos.
Ustedes están no solamente está mamá para acompañarlo,
papá, los hermanos, la familia,
sino que estamos en la iglesia,
pero lo mejor de todo es que el Señor Jesucristo
está con ustedes y el Señor Jesucristo
los ama tanto que el dio la vida
para que ustedes puedan tener vida
y vida en abundancia.
También y Diego,
son tres decisiones importantes que hacemos en la vida.
¿Sabe cuáles son las tres decisiones más importantes en la vida?
Aceptar a Dios
y...
siempre creer en Dios
que siempre sepas que Dios siempre va a ser contigo
y nunca te va a abandonar.
Ahí va, ahí va el camino.
La primera es esa decisión.
No habló de novia ahí.
Pero la primera decisión es esa.
Ustedes son muy valientes
y usted es un testimonio para los que están llegando,
creciendo, que se van a utilizar un día.
La segunda decisión es cómo vas a traer las tortillas a la mesa.
Hay que estudiar
y graduarse.
Vale la pena sufrir cinco, seis años,
unos días en la universidad
pero poder tener una graduación.
Y la última decisión,
la última pero la tercera
con quién pasará el resto de su vida.
Una esposa que ame a Dios.
Amém?
Por ahora preocupa-se con esta decisión
y estudiar.
Amém?
Así que...
con mucha alegría
nosotros tenemos como pastores en esta mañana
ese privilegio
de seguir lo que Jesús nos dice
de predicar el Evangelio,
llevar las personas a Cristo
y bautizarlas, pues
es un privilegio, pastor,
y una alegría para nosotros en esta mañana
como ministros del Evangelio
seguiendo las órdenes del Mestre Jesús
para remisión de sus pecados
y para una vida con Cristo.
Pastor Riso y yo les bautizamos
en el nombre del Padre, del Hijo
y del Espíritu Santo
y la Iglesia de Dios dice...
...
honor and remembering the memory of my friend.
And yesterday we saw that she re-bautized herself.
And she put something very special,
because she put, on September 5,
I died together with Dani.
But on September 5, I also decided to live again.
And she made this decision to re-bautize herself,
because what you see now is that.
When a person decides to surrender to Jesus,
he decides to live again.
He decides to face, even though it is difficult,
even though we have lived terrible things,
today we have decided, and every day we can decide,
to live again, to be reborn.
Jesus said, all those who are in Christ
is a new creature.
I don't know what you have faced.
Maybe today you are also in the middle
of celebrating beautiful things,
but also to regret things deeply sad.
I want to remind you that the world is of God,
that He is sovereign, that He continues to be king,
and even though dark seems evil,
He continues to be king.
And today, I want to speak to your heart,
so that today you also decide to be reborn.
Sing with us this hymn called, World,
and remember, even though dark seems evil,
He continues to be king.
The world is my father, and I can see it.
La natura les acantas lo bueno que hace
El mundo es de mi padre
Y en cada manse
La luz de la mañana
Me muestra su poder
El mundo es de mi padre
Me alegra de saber
Que aunque eternal parezca el mal
Él sigue siendo mi...
Cántalo con el corazón
El mundo es de mi padre
Me alegra sin pensar
Que mi vida está en sus manos
Y puedo descansar
El mundo es de mi padre
Yo jamás lo olvidaré
Que aunque eternal parezca el mal
Él sigue siendo el rey
Recordarte que ya está Jesús dispuesto a tomar tu mano y hacerte caminar por sobre el mar
Porque no cantas otra vez y hoy le entregas tu vida entera
Y decides volver a comenzar
Y decides que él sigue siendo el rey de tu vida
Vamos a cantar si el mundo entero está sus pies
Cántalo junto a nosotros
Si el mundo entero está sus pies
Y entonces yo también
Si la tierra canta su poder
Entonces yo también
Si el mundo entero está sus pies
Si la tierra canta su poder
Entonces yo también
El mundo es de mi padre
Jamás, jamás lo olvidaré
Que aunque eternal parezca el mal
Él sigue siendo el rey
Aunque eternal parezca el mal
Y hoy hemos venido a levantar el nombre de Jesús en este lugar
A poder decir que él es lo único que necesitamos
Para seguir adelante
Así que te invito a medida que cantamos este canto lema de la serie de la apocalipsis
A que vayas pasando aquí delante si hoy quieres tener una oración especial con Dios
Vamos a cantar, vamos a declarar que Jesús sigue siendo el rey en este momento
Luz en las tinielas
Luz que todo llena
Nos inclinamos
Y te adoramos Jesús
Luz
Verbo en el principio
Tú que has venido
Para salvarnos
Y perdonarnos
Jesús
Solo tu nombre
Es suficiente
Para calmarte
Solo tu gracia
Esperanza
Que nos da vida
Que toda la gloria
Sea ti, Jesús
El es vida en la muerte y nadie le hace frente
Vida en la muerte
Nadie te hace frente
O te saltamos
Y te adoramos Jesús
Cuando no hay sentido eres el camino
Cuanto no hay sentido
Que eres el camino
Que encontramos
Lo que anhelamos
Jesús
Solo tu nombre
Es suficiente
Para calmarte
Solo tu gracia
Esperanza
Que nos da vida
Que toda la gloria
Sea ti, Jesús
Que sea ti, Jesús
Solo tu nombre
Es suficiente
Para calmarte
Solo tu gracia
Esperanza
Que nos da vida
Que toda la gloria
Sea ti, Jesús
Si viniste hoy a la mañana es buscando qué el Señor tiene para decirnos
Seguimos orando por nuestra hermana Lucia Malla, ella está con cáncer
Los doctores, en las últimas semanas que he estado hablando con ella
Me dijo, pastor, los doctores ya me desahuciaron
Dicen, no hay nada para hacer
El Señor puede hacer un milagro en ella
Y si no pasar a eso ahora
Aún el descanso, dice el apóstol Pablo
El pasar al descanso es una ganancia
Porque nuestro destino está sellado
Aunque para los seres humanos la muerte pueda parecer lo último
Aún eso es una bendición
Aunque parezca paradójico
Oramos también por varios de nuestras familias y hermanos
Que tienen situaciones migratorias
Y en las próximas semanas estarán teniendo diferentes entrevistas
Que el Señor pueda obrar en cada uno de ellos también en sus familias
Vamos a postrarnos, vamos a rodizarnos y vamos a pedir la bendición de Dios
Querido y amante padre que estás en los cielos
Señor, en este momento estamos puestos de rodilla delante de ti
En señal de sumisión
Seguramente hemos luchado, intentado
Solucionar nuestras cosas muchas veces
Queremos hacerlo solo, señor
Y nos hemos dado cuenta que nos vamos a ningún lado
Nos seguimos hundiendo cada vez más
Señor, confiamos en ti, confiamos en tu palabra, tus promesas
Queremos colocarnos cada uno de los que estamos aquí, señor
En tus manos de amor
Ahora vamos a abrir tu palabra
Y pedimos que tu Espíritu Santo sea el que pueda guiar nuestra mente
Nuestro corazón y nuestra atención
Señor, el enemigo intentará poner distracciones aquí
Distraer nuestra mente, nuestro corazón
Que nuestra mente empiece a divagar por ahí
Señor, no permitas que eso pase
Que nos podamos concentrar en lo que tú quieres decirnos hoy
Lo pedimos y lo agradecemos todo en el nombre de Jesucristo Ramos
Amen, y amen, señor
Hoy yo siempre amaré esa cruz
Canta, no tú conoces
En sus triunfos mi gloria será
Y algún día en fes de una cruz
Mi corona Jesús me dará
Amen
Muy felizado para todos
Felizado para todos
Qué alegría es encontrarnos en la casa del señor
Dispuestos a oír qué es lo que el señor quiere decirnos hoy
Estamos con una serie
La serie del libro del apocalipsis
Y la propuesta que les lancé
Cuando comenzamos con esta serie
Fue poder encontrar a lo largo del libro
El apocalipsis cuáles son los retratos que aparecen
Del mismo señor Jesús
Y vamos a tener ocho temas juntos
Compartiendo diferentes retratos
Ya hablamos, comenzamos con el alfa y la omega
Comenzamos con el cordero
El anterior fue el león de juda
El cordero transformándose el león
Y el tema de esta mañana
Lleva por título el gran pastor
Y vamos a identificar una figura que a mí
Personalmente me gusta
Aunque ya les había dicho que la figura del león de juda
Me gusta mucho también
Son características diferentes que el apóstol Juan
Escribe o relata de lo que él recibe
Como orientación de parte del señor
Cuando le he revelado el libro del apocalipsis
Y en esta mañana vamos a ver ahora
El cordero transformándose
Y produciendo una especie
Casi podríamos decir como de metamorfosis
Convertiéndose el cordero
Convertiéndose en un pastor
Y qué paradójico es porque el cordero
Pero esa es la capacidad que nuestro señor tiene
Y tú y yo no tenemos un dios
Que simplemente sea alguien
Que ha muerto por ti nada más
Como el cordero
Si no alguien que puede llegar a ser
Tu sanador y tu restaurador
En este tiempo en que necesitamos
De un pastor
Y no estamos hablando aquí
De un pastor humano
Como los que tenemos aquí en la iglesia
O los que tienen ustedes aquí en la iglesia
Con todas nuestras fallas
Todos nuestros defectos
Toda la forma de caminar
Ustedes dicen no
Pero no me gusta la forma como caminar el pastor
Porque camina medio así
Y tú puedes ver todas las fallas
Y todos los errores en cada uno de nosotros
Pero cuando comenzamos a ver
Ahora ya no a la figura del pastor humano
Si no comenzamos a ver la figura
De Jesucristo como el pastor
Ahí entonces el sentido de nuestra vida
Cambia profundamente
Y entonces a manera de repaso
De lo que venimos dialogando
Durante estos días vamos así
Al libro de Apocalipsia el capítulo 5
Versículo 12 que te dije
Que a mi entender por lo menos
Y podemos discutir en esto
A mi entender el texto central
O el texto clave del libro del apocalipsia
Es el capítulo 5
Versículo 12 que algunos pueden argumentar
Y pueden decir no para el pastor
Para mí lo más importante es esto
Otro y este otro texto de aquí
Capítulo 5 versículo 12
Dice y que decían a gran voz
¿Quiénes decían a gran voz?
El versículo 11 decía y merece y oí la voz
De muchos ángeles alrededor del trono
Y de seres vivientes y los ancianos
Y su número eran millones de millones
Que decían a gran voz, dice el versículo 12
El cordero que fue inmolado
Es digno de tomar el poder
La riqueza, la sabiduría, la fortaleza
La honra, la gloria y la alabanza
Y estas son características de la adoración
Que van a ser repetidas y de paso
Hoy vamos a ver algunos versículos donde se repite
Esa secuencia o esas características
De cómo debe ser nuestra adoración
O cómo debe estar, dónde debe estar
Sentrada tu adoración y la mía
Y que tiene que ver con el lugar
Que ahora le es devuelto a Jesucristo
No solamente como el cordero
Que murió así en la cruz
Y que Juan lo había visto
Y que lo describe así en el Evangelio
Si, en el Evangelio de Juan
Sino que ahora casi como un efecto
Podríamos decir continuado
Él recibe la revelación del libro
El Apocalipsis pero lo ve ahora totalmente
Transformado a ese cordero que había sido
Imolado, a ese cordero que había sido
Muerto, que produjo un chasco
Y algunos le llaman como una especie
De primer gran chasco que los discípulos
Tienen cuando lo ven ahora
Colgado a Jesús de la cruz
Porque ellos pensaban, si, ellos creían
Verdaderamente que Jesús era el Hijo de Dios
Que venía a cumplir una misión
De ser el Messiah, ellos creían
Pero decía ahora, él va a terminar
Con nuestra esclavitud que tenemos
Con respecto al gobierno romano
Y entonces la nación judía
El pueblo de Israel ahora
Va a ser puesto otra vez
En la primera plana del mundo entero
Y ellos creyeron esto
Y se creyeron
Y se hicieron como una
Comenzaron a tener
Como ciertas ideas en su cabeza
Con respecto a esto
Y quién va a estar en el primer lugar
Y a la izquierda y a la derecha
Discutiendo y peleando sobre cosas
Para las cuales el Señor Jesucristo
No había venido
Jesucristo había venido para hacer un ciervo
Para hacer un cordero que iba a morir
En la cruz y que le iba a producir
Hasta vergüenza a ellos
Para tener seguidores de Jesús
Como le pasó a Pedro
El gran Pedro que decía yo
Si tengo que dar la vida por ti
Claro, dar la vida por ti
Cuando tengamos que ir a pelear
Para hacer que tú seas el rey
Y ponerte ahora en lugar de rey
Pero no para pelear por mi vida
Porque si no me van a perseguir
Y me van a tomar y me van a crucificar
A mí como te van a crucificar a ti
Y esa fue la gran
Dissociación que hubo
En la mente y en los corazones
De estos discípulos
Y entonces ahora de pronto lo ven
A Jesucristo colgado
Ahí pendiendo de la cruz
Como algo, algún plan
Pasión mal, señor
Te equivocaste en algo, no?
Alguna cosa te tiene que haber equivocado
Pero ahora unos poquitos años
Después de que recibiera
Y que escribiera el Evangelio
De San Juan, ahora
El mismo apóstolo de San Juan
See the revelation
Of the book of the Apocalypse
We said that the meaning
Different from what we've been
And I told you since I was a child
That the revelation was God
Revealing what was going to happen
In the future and look at all of this
And I remember the seminars
When I was a child
A brother
Of the church, the brother
Ruben came to our house
And then we had seminars
Of Holy Weeks, seminars
Of Apocalypse
And then with the little machine
Do you remember the little machine
That used to go through?
The projector of the little one
Do you remember that little machine?
You're from the last century
We millennia are
This
Well, I remember that little machine
That used to go through
The little ones, right?
It was
How beautiful that new camera
That we have, thanks to the
The group that allowed us to buy
And what if one comes out
You have to make up a little
For that camera, right?
If all the arrugas come out
And things like that
We're going little by little
Improving our transmissions
So we thank you
For the loyalty of each of you
In this
What was I saying?
The little machine
Yes, but it had already advanced
The German says some
What is it?
From Ruben, there it is, thanks, thanks
The brother Ruben came
And passed the slides
In my house
And then he showed the images
Of what was going to happen
What I had to see with the signs
What is part of
The book of the Apocalypse
It presents as such
So that you and I are alerted
Of what happened, but it's not the center of the Apocalypse
It is
The center of the Apocalypse has to do with this
Chapter 1, verse 1
It says that it's
The revelation of Jesus Christ
And we say that
That concept of revelation of Jesus Christ
Is the revelation that Jesus Christ presents
That is being revealed
The same, Lord Jesus Christ
As for the salvific functions
That Jesus Christ has for his people
And then
Different images
And different portraits of Jesus
Throughout the book of the Apocalypse
That we are prefigured
Of what Jesus Christ was going to do
In the final time
And how we can fully trust
That is the work that Jesus Christ
Is going to be Salvador
As we have already seen
Being the first and the last
Who is from the beginning, from always
And who will be forever
And so you and I don't have
A God, a Salvador
Who had a beginning
And someone came and created it
And said, look, you have to do this
Or are you going to do this or are you going to do your function
No, because Jesus Christ is eternal
And it's from the beginning
Although within the human mind
We can't understand or understand
The eternity of Jesus
How Jesus Christ can be eternal
And then some say no
The Father is only eternal
The Son is created by God
Being that is a concept
That is not theological
That we don't accept as such
Jesus Christ enjoys the full
The full attributes
As God fully
Being eternal and being eternal
Is from always and forever
Alpha and Omega
So we are in
That time
Of God and Jesus Christ
And we are
Considered
Dictators of having that kind
Of God and not a God
Anyone simply
The concept that we saw
About Jesus Christ as the lamb
As who came to give
His blood and his death
Came to do our
Our guarantee
Of salvation
We have the figure
Of the lion of Judah
The lamb transforming
The lion that was the previous figure
Or the previous portrait that we saw
Of Jesus, a lion is someone
Who can fight for you
And for me in a significant way
No
And
The topic today has to do
With Jesus Christ now
Transforming himself into a pastor
Some
Statistic data
To somehow sit down
The basis of what we are going to
Dialogue or throughout this morning
There are statistics
You can find different statistics
On the internet about this
But between the year 23
And the year 24
2023-2024
These are statistics from here
From the United States
33.5 of the adults reported
My depression
Being the prevalence of women
36% and men 30%
I was thinking
Why would it be
The men's fault
So
33% of the adults reported
A symptom of anxiety and depression
Between the young people
Between 18 and 29
The prevalence was
Higher
I always remember
The anxiety and depression
For the oldest
Look
Between 18 and 29
The prevalence was
Almost 50%
At some point
They reported symptoms of anxiety
And depression
What else?
The 20.3% of the teenagers
Between 12 and 17
Years
They had
A diagnosis that included
Anxiety, depression
And other diseases related to this
The 20.3%
One
Of each
Five
About
The 20% of the teenagers
Between 10 and 17
Has tried to commit suicide
Or has had a suicide attempt
Throughout his life
The 10%
Of each 10
I saw here
There were children
A little less than 10 years
But a few weeks ago
When we finished the program
Reset, we passed
The teenagers
Between 13 and 18
And 20 years
And we had 60
In the front
So I thought
When I prepared this message
According to the statistics
Six
At least
Have had suicide attempts
Have tried to commit suicide
Of course
You could say no, but from here
Of these children that we have here
No, because they have another vision
But these are the things
With which
Our children face
Maybe they haven't tried
To commit suicide
That has gone through this situation
And maybe you get in the way
Of someone
As I always say
When we say
To a mother
Who has lost her son
Who killed her son in a crime
She says, but in the city
She heard these days
The superintendent of an Argentinian city
That said, but in this city
We have lowered the crime acts
The murderers were
Of hundreds
Of homicides that there were
Now we are in 40
Congratulations
It's only you, son
Who killed her
So the statistics
Are completely blurred
And they fall because you say
That's my son
And maybe some of the parents
Who are here
Are seeing that their children
Are going through this situation
In the ethereal part of the adults
So the 33.5 of the adults
At some point
Report symptoms of anxiety
And depression
Or maybe you are in the part
Of the young adults between 18 and 29 years old
Or maybe you are
In the part of the teenagers
You are in the part
That you are
We are exposed to these situations
And these problems
What we think today
Is the result of our wounds
Of the past
Of remorse
Of the lives of the children
Of happy or sad
That we have had
But my child was a happy child
I had a good time
That's what you express now
In this time
But maybe your child
Has not been a happy child
Maybe you had to face
Traumas, abuse
Hurts of the past
People who hurt you
And even after 30 or 40
50 years
That you are suffering
All those things you could not
Solve those situations
These days I talked
With some family
And they told me
How they had started
Their experiences together
And this happened more than 20 years
And this was traumatic
And it has consequences today
Those things
Because they are wounds that are still open
And that we have not been able to solve
Because we have not been able to manage
Those situations
For different reasons
Maybe we don't have the tools to do it
We don't know how to do it
We take a shortcut
To try to solve those things
What we think today
And how we act today
Are results of all those things
That have happened
But let's go to the book of Salmo
Chapter 34, verse 7
And we found, I put it down there
Look at the same head of security
The same head of security
What does this mean?
The angel of Jehová
Says the psalmist there
David in Psalm 34 verse 7
The same angel of Jehová
Is around those who fear him
And what does he do?
And he defends them
That is the figure of the same Lord Jesus Christ
That is, the same Lord Jesus Christ
Is around you and me
And this I told you
That during my childhood
They taught me that Jesus Christ
When he came to this land
And took the human nature
Lost the capacity
Of being able to be
In every place that is called
Omnipresence
Thank you
Lost the capacity of omnipresence
What a tremendous thing that human beings
Sometimes say
About Jesus
Then we have certain ideas
This is a satanic idea
I want to tell you
Because it is to lower
The level
To Jesus Christ
Of the capacities
That he still has
As God
Still being fully God
But it is also fully human
Now it is even more
Of what was before
Jesus Christ
Is that angel of Jehová
The angel of Jehová
Jesus Christ himself
Is around those who fear him
And defends them
Jesus Christ
Is by your side
That is why I told you
In the slide
The same chief of security
If you want to send a subject
To say, go and take care
Jesus Christ himself
Is by your side
As the great pastor
And then we go to the book of Revelation
Chapter 6, verse 12
Up to 17
Book of Revelation
Chapter 6, verse 12
Chapter 17 says
And when the sixth seal opens
Something interesting happens here
That is the opening of the sixth seal
If you look here
In chapter 6
You can start reading the different seals
And the different stages
Or moments in which the seals are open
And we had seen
In a previous message
I think two messages back
You can search here on YouTube
To see the series
In the previous themes
In this series
And then we talked and said
That is the
Envergadura or the magnitude
Of the importance of the message
That now God is revealing
To his people
And says the revelation of Jesus Christ
That God gave him
And sent the message to his angel
And the angel gave it to Juan
And the angel gave it to the seven churches
That is what we know as
The chain of prophetic revelation
And then that message appears
Saying
That it was so important
That it had to be sealed
With seven seals
It's not a message
Any of the ones we found
Here in the book of the Apocalypse
It's a message for the time
Of the end
And it's a message
That now the seals begin to be open
The seals were placed
To give the importance
That something was being done
Important on the one hand
That it was being sealed
But now the seals begin to open
In different moments
And here appears what we know as
The opening of the sixth seal
And it was here that there was a big earthquake
The sun became black as a cell
The moon became all blood
And here some argue and say
Well, this happened in 1700
I don't even remember the date
In 1855, 1800 and so
This happened here
Because in a place in the United States
There was a star
It was part of it
But this has to do with
A much bigger event
And that it's the same
What appears here in the slide
That it's the same day of Jehovah
The same day of the second coming
Of Christ is when the opening
Of the sixth seal is produced
When the sixth seal was opened
There was a big earthquake
The day of the coming of Jesus
Second coming
And the sun became black
And the moon became all blood
And the stars of the sky fell on the earth
Like the eagle leaves its tail
When it's held by a strong wind
And the sky became a parchment
That rolls
And all the mountains and all the islands
Were removed from their place
And the kings of the earth and the greats
The rich and the captains
The powerful, all servants, all free
They hid in the caves
And among the peonies of the mountains
And they said to the mountains
About the throne and the eagle of the lamb
Because the great day of his coming
And who
Will be able to hold on
Who
And then comes what we know
Now as the answer
In chapter 7 comes the answer
That now Juan hears
Of the question that is made
In chapter 6, verse 17
In that moment when the sixth seal
Is opened
Who will be able to hold on
What is going to happen?
The stars were going to fall
The sun was going to darken
The moon was going to become blood
The sky was going to roll
Like a parchment
A
Catastrophic disaster
We could say
And when you read it
It scares you
And people say
I don't want to know anything
About the apocalypse
Because it is a disaster
And I don't want to
But when I tell you
That disaster
That is written there
But there will be something
That will give you full certainty
And full security
Chapter 7
Verse 2 to 4
You can read it
You can read the whole chapter 6
And the full chapter 7
Of the Holy Saturday
For example
And a group of people
Appears
That are sealed by the Lord
That are separated
To be sealed, to be separated
To receive a special brand
Of part of the Lord Jesus
For what?
Chapter 7, verse 2 to 4
These are going to receive a special care
Of part of the Lord Jesus
Verse 2 says
An angel who rose
From where the sun comes
Because I had already seen in chapter 7
Verse 1
I had already seen 4 angels
Now it looks like it is a 5th angel
That appears there
I also saw another angel
Who rose from where the sun comes
And had the seal of the living God
And called the 4 angels
Who had given them the power
To hurt the earth and the sea
And told them
To the trees
Until what?
Tell them
Until we have sealed
In front of them
To whom?
And today the number of the sealed
144,000 sealed
Of all the tribes of the children
That is a reason
Of discussion for some
And many too
This number is literal
Symbolic
We believe it is a symbolic number
It is not a literal number
It is representing the people of God
That they will be sealed
In the final time
That they will receive a special distinction
Why?
Because they were the servants of God
And then
So they do not do it
Until we call them
Why?
Because they were going to receive a special care
So your concern and mine
Should not be
What will happen in the final time?
What will happen if the sky
And the star will fall?
What will happen if
You have to worry
If I am receiving the seal
Of God or not
Because the Lord clearly says
The Lord will protect me
And He will protect you and me
In a special way
When we are apart
We are sealed by Him
And that should be your concern and mine
In the hands of the Lord
One of those things
That happen to you
Are allowed and are with a purpose
One of those things
That he says because he does not say
Look, this will not happen
To those who receive the seal
It can be that you touch you
It can be that you receive something
But it can be that those things
Take a different path
Because the Lord when He is allowing
Something in your life and mine
Is with a purpose
And then I put down there
In this slide, when you are on the other side
Of the river
Do you remember some messages
In this same series
I said that sometimes we are in those intermediate
When I was talking about Alpha and Omega
People told you that story of when we were
Going to the river in Argentina
And then we started swimming
And suddenly it was a river that
More or less had about 100 meters
Of width and we had
Ten, eleven years and we were swimming
In that river that was tremendously
Caudaloso deep in the part
In the middle had
I do not know, more than 10 meters
Easily more than 30 feet
And we were swimming
And sometimes when I was in the middle
Of the river
But at the same time I was
Going back and I was going to throw again
Because that's how we are human beings
We are half kamikaze
But then when you are
In the middle of the river
He says, what happens sir
And then sometimes I ask
And I say, sir
When something happens to me in my life
Something that is happening to me
In what season
Of hop would this happen to me
The season
When before
I received the blessings from God
I am sure that something bad
Has to have come out
It was not all perfect
Still in that time of blessings
Previous to what came after
Then came a time where he lost
Absolutely everything
Lost health, lost
The animals, lost their children
The wife left him, how good
He was left without sweat
But then what happened
After the lord returns him
The double
He returned his wife
He was going to have two eggs
He was going to make a cow
One wife
And that's what the lord now returns
And I am sure
That after that he continued
Receiving some
Negative things in his life
Because he was living in this world
It was not all perfect
The lord
In what season of hop life
Is this happening to me
Is this happening in the first season
Is this happening to me in the middle
Where everything is bad
And yesterday I talked to someone
That said to me
Everything is bad
And I am not going to tell
The details
Because if you don't realize who
Everything is bad
But everything is bad
In sickness
I am not going to say it
Or that you are in the third stage
Where you
In some way start to enjoy
The blessings of god
After having passed
That river
After being on the other side of the river
And start to enjoy
The joy and peace that the lord gives us
But there is a process for that
And our life
We are in the process
In the process of what?
In the process of restoration
In the process of reconstruction
Chapter 7 verse 9
It says after this
Look here a great multitude
That nobody could count
That they were dressed for the occasion
I put it like this
And they were from all nations
Tribes, towns and languages
That were in front of the throne
And in the presence of the lamb
Those white dresses
That they receive
Not because they deserve it
But because this has to do with the good works
There is a book
That I love
That is called
Sumanto o El Mio
You can try to dress
With your own cloak
And the theme is
The cloak of justice
The own justice
And we are going to see the book
That our justice
Are like the cloak of immundity
Our justice
What does this mean?
That we cannot do absolutely nothing
To receive salvation for our own account
When you try
To sanctify yourself
For your own account, all you do
Is sink you more and more
But it says in the book of Romans
Chapter 5 verse 1
Justified
For the faith
We have peace for whom
It begins to be in peace for God
We receive the white dresses
And the dress that will be delivered
When Jesus Christ comes to look for us
For a second time
A white dress
Totally purple
What has been, look
Your black dresses stained
By sin and mine
Our dresses stained by sin
These are the works
Of our life completely by sin
Now it passes
By the blood of Jesus Christ
And your blood and mine
What do you do with your clothes?
Your blood and mine, what do you do with your clothes?
The stain
And you don't take away the stain of blood
But when our
Our life passes
By the blood of Jesus Christ
We receive the white dresses
Completely white
The purity that only the blood
Of Jesus Christ can give
But there's something to do
Pastor, you have nothing to do
That's the moment
When Jesus Christ, when you give
To the Father, He says
Sir, I accept Jesus Christ
As my Savior, the Lord Jesus Christ
He died for me in the cross
And then the Father cleans your life
And mine of sin
And then He gives me the white dresses
And now I begin to live
As I have received
Those white dresses
That's the next step
That's the process of sanctification
And no one is saying
Pastor, you're saying that it doesn't matter
No, I'm not saying that it doesn't matter
How you and I live
Now we have to live
As I have received
The cleansing of the blood of Christ
And one day
Your life is going to stain
Because you're going to fall
And you're not going to criticize someone
You're not going to be with something that doesn't
Corresponds to you, you're going to lie
Or whatever
But then
Now comes the next step
That is the process of the request
Again, forgive me, sir
Look, I've fallen and the Lord will forgive you
The Lord gives you the opportunity
To clean again
Your dresses
In the blood of the Lord Jesus Christ
Chapter 7, verse 11
And all the angels were standing
Around the throne
And of the ancients and of the four survivors
And they bet on their faces in front of the throne
And they adored and said
Amen
The blessing and the glory and the wisdom
And the action of grace and the honor
And the power and the strength
Be ours
Be ours, God, for the centuries of the centuries
And here we have what we know
As the seven expressions of prayer
And in the verse 13
The ancients spoke to me
These who are dressed in white clothes
Who are they?
And where have they come from?
The ancients asking Juan
And I told him, sir
You're the one who knows
You came to ask me, you're the one who knows
And he told me, these are the ones
Who have left the Great Tribulation
And washed their clothes
And have blanched them
In the blood of the lamb
For this, they are in front of the throne
Of God and serve him day and night
In his temple, and the one who is
Centered on the throne
He will extend his tabernacle
On them, his justice
The justice of these
Were like a trap of immundity
But they delivered
Their lives in the hands of the Lord
And the Lord forgave them
He gave them the new opportunity
Verse 15 said
And the one who is sitting on the throne
Will have no more tabernacles on them
And they will no longer be hungry
Verse 16 said
And the sun will no longer fall on them
Nor any heat
Because the lamb
Who is in the middle of the throne
Will destroy them
And will guide them
From the waters of life
And God will play all the tears
Of his eyes
Or of their eyes
This is the figure
The lamb
Who was your savior and mine
Now transforming into a pastor
And saying, it doesn't matter
For the season that you are going through
In your life
It doesn't matter for the situations
That you are going through in your life today
It may be that you are going through
A situation of
Of disease
Of cancer
Of divorce
It may be that you are going through
Why?
You know it
And I won't ask you to say it now
But it may be that you are going through
Those situations
But the Lord says to you, I now
Transform into your pastor
I am not only your savior
I am the one who can clean
Your life of sin
Through my blood
I now transform into the true pastor
That we all need
And that is Jesus
For a few years
This happened several years ago
Once I asked the pastor
Alejandro Bullona, traveling in the car
Together
I said, pastor, when you say
The other day
Ah, it happened 40 years ago
You tell me
And you realize this
This happened
In the year 2000
Camila Rizzo had
One year
25 years
The old Camila
We love you
And
2000, year 2000
You have two ways to know
If you are old
One when you start telling stories
That happened 40 years ago
And the other is when you go to Six Flags
And it decomposes and starts to vomit
That is another symptom of being old
I remember one day
Pablo, do you remember that we were there
We found a case and I was vomiting
Dr. Pablo gave me a little drama
Mine I think
And there it improved
But I couldn't go back to the game
They are symptoms
We are getting old
We were working
In a district
In the south of the province of Córdoba
In Argentina
District of Río Cuarto
We have some churches there
We were starting our ministry
And
We also had to attend a city
The city of La Bulaya
It was about four hours away
A city of about 30,000 inhabitants
There was no adventist presence
More than just one adventist
And we started to work
To plant a church
So we went
Imagine four hours
Saturday morning
We went there early
We left 5
In the morning
About 10
We were there all day
And at night
We started the return trip
And between the city of La Bulaya
And the city of La Carlota
That was another city there
In the middle of the road
We had
A route that was a route
That was quite narrow
From one side to the other
It wasn't cold
And like here
One goes through a cold
On any side
There was no sign
At night
When I say no sign
No sign
It was a route
About 150 km
About 100 miles
There was no gas
In the middle
There was absolutely nothing
If you wanted to go to the bathroom
Don't stop
Totally dark
The area of some lagoon
Around like this
It wasn't a swamp
But it looked like a swamp
What made it a bit more tetric
Imagine at night
So when I
Traveled there with Mariela
And Camila that we had only Camila
Traveled
I was in the middle of the road
And to the maximum that I had
In my car that wasn't much
But the maximum that I had
If we see something in front
You sit here and I
I walk over it
Be it person or whatever
Because it was like this
Well, many times we did that trip
At night
So I go that night
That Saturday night
So fast
And at the distance
I see the lights
Of a car that was on the side of the road
So I tell my wife
I say, look, there's a car parked
But then
I come in the middle, I throw a little
More here and I say
Prepare anything
And I go like this
And I see it like this
A car
A Chevy
SS
Here it's called Chevy Nova
For those who know the car
For women it's like this
It doesn't work
And when I pass
I see it
to
Martin
Daniel
Victor
That were there
They were like the two in the morning
And then I pass like this
And when I pass
I see that they were there
And they go like this
Like crazy
And then I brake
Like 100
100 meters forward
And I go back
And when I'm coming
Like this, about here
Where the camera is
I stop the car
And I go down
And these guys there
They were young, young adults
The pastor
They say, we've never had
I wanted to see the pastor
He says, if you've made me go bad
Pastor, please, sorry
Never again, we're going to make you go bad
I say, the man takes care of them
In the lake and you suffer
I say
They had gone fishing
That Saturday afternoon
After the sunset
To the area of the lagoon
And when they came back
The car was left
Without gasoline
And there was no gasoline
And they say
It's been about two hours
And it didn't even happen
And they said, it's not going to happen
Because it doesn't happen
And if someone passes
Nobody will stop you
And you're going to have to go
There's no public transport
And they say, well, we take a collective
A base
They say, pastor, we've never had
So much joy to see it
And I thought
How many times
We go through those situations
In our lives
I told them
That the night could have been
Very long for you
We had to go to the next town
To look for gasoline
And then go back
And be able to put them
To continue the trip
And continue the trip together
How many times
We can be going through
Those dark situations
In our lives
And it may be that
Your time
Whether you're going through
A very long night
You say
Sir, when will this night end?
And suddenly you look
And look up
And you see Jesus
And you scream
Pastor
And not a human pastor
But the best pastor
That you and I can have
That is the Lord Jesus
How many of you want to say
In this morning to the Lord
Lord, I'm living at night
But I want you
To be my true pastor
I'm going to see your hand
I'm going to invite the worshiper
To come forward to sing
While
You stand up
Where you are
We're going to sing
The first verse of the song
Jesus
The song that
We're singing for this series
Where
The lyrics of this song
Tell us
Everything that the Lord Jesus
Can do in your life
And in mine
He is the
The great pastor
That you and I can have
The Lord Jesus
Luz en las tinielas
Luz que todo llena
Nos inclinamos
Y te adoramos
Jesus
Verbo en el principio
O tú que has venido
Para salvarnos
Y perdonarnos
Jesus
Si cantemos con el corazón
Solo tu nombre
Es suficiente
Para calmar la tempesta
Solo tu gracia
Es la esperanza
Que nos da vida
De verdad
Que toda la gloria
Sea a ti
Jesus
Amante Padre
Gracias por Jesus
Gracias por el gran pastor
Gracias por que
En los tiempos de oscuridad
Nosotros estamos seguro
Que ese cordero nos pastoriará
Señores
La figura de Jesus es increíble
Gracias por eso
El nombre de Jesucristo oramos
Amen
Con las sociedades jóvenes bendiciones
Y feliz sábado